the following is a conversation with
以下是与之对话
Petera Beal he's a professor UC Berkeley
Petera Beal他是 加州大学伯克利分校 的教授
and the director of the Berkeley
还有伯克利的导演
robotics learning lab he's one of the
机器人 学习实验室 他是其中之一
top researchers in the world working on
世界 上最优秀的研究人员
how we make robots understand and
我们 如何 让机器人 了解和
interact with the world around them
与周围 的 世界互动
especially using imitation and deeper
特别是使用模仿和更深层次
enforcement learning this conversation
执法学习这个对话
is part of the MIT course and artificial
是麻省理工学院课程和人工课程的一部分
general intelligence and the artificial
一般情报和人工
intelligence podcast if you enjoy it
智能播客，如果你喜欢 它
please subscribe on YouTube iTunes where
请 在 YouTube iTunes上 订阅
your podcast provider of choice or
您选择的播客提供商或
simply connect with me on Twitter at Lex
只需在Twitter的Twitter上与我联系
Friedman spelled Fri D and now here's my
弗里德曼拼写了Fri D，现在这里是我的
conversation with Peter a Biel you've
和Peter a Biel谈话你
mentioned that if there was one person
提到如果有 一个人
you could meet you'll be Roger Federer
你能见到你的是罗杰·费德勒
so let me ask when do you think we will
那么让我问你认为我们什么时候会这样做
have a robot that fully autonomously can
有一个完全自主的机器人
beat Roger Federer at tennis Roger
在网球 罗杰击败罗杰·费德勒
Federer level player at tennis huh well
网球的费德勒级别球员很好
first if you can make it happen for me
首先，如果你能让 它 成为我的事
to meet Roger let me know terms of
见到罗杰 让我知道 条款
getting a robot to beat him at tennis
让一个机器人在网球比赛中击败他
it's kind of an interesting question
这是一个有趣的问题
because for a lot of the challenges we
因为我们面临很多挑战
think about in AI the software is really
在AI中考虑软件是 真的
the missing piece but for something like
缺少一块但是喜欢的东西
this the hardware is nowhere near either
这个 硬件也远不是
like to really have a robot that can
喜欢真的有 一个 可以 的机器人
physically run around the Boston
在波士顿周围跑来跑去
Dynamics robots are starting to get
动力机器人开始变得越来越好
there but still not really human level
那里但仍然不是真正的人类水平
ability to to run around and then swing
要 跑来跑去，然后摆动能力
a racket that's a hardware problem I
一个球拍，这是一个硬件问题我
don't think it's a harder problem only I
不要以为它仅仅是一个困难的问题 我
think it's a hardware and a software
认为这是硬件和软件
problem I think it's both and I think
问题我认为这两者都是 我想的
they'll they'll have independent
他们会独立的
progress so I'd say the the hardware
进步所以我会说硬件
maybe in 10-15 years I'm just late not
也许 10到15年我才迟到
grass I've dressed with a sliding yeah
草我穿着滑动 是啊
oh plague I'm not sure what's Carter
哦瘟疫我不确定卡特是什么
grass or clay the clay involves sliding
草或粘土粘土涉及滑动
which might be harder to master actually
实际上可能更难掌握
yeah but you're not limited to bipedal I
是的，但你不仅 限于双足 我
mean I'm sure there's I can build a
意思是我确定我可以建立一个
machine it's a whole different question
机器这是一个完全 不同的问题
of course you know
当然你知道
you can if you can say okay this robot
如果你 能说这个 机器人 就可以了
can be on wheels they can move around on
可 在轮子上 ，他们可以 围绕 移动
wheels and can be designed differently
轮子，可以设计 不同
then I think that that can be done
那么我认为那可以 做到
sooner probably than a full humanoid
可能比一个完整的人形机器人更快
type of setup what do you think is swing
设置的类型你认为是什么样的 摇摆
a racket so you've worked at basic
一个球拍， 所以你 在基本工作
manipulation how hard do you think is
操纵你觉得有多难
the task of swinging or racket would be
摆动或球拍的任务是
able to hit a nice backhand or a
能够 打一个漂亮的反手或
forehand
正手
okay let's say let's say we just set up
好吧，让我们说我们刚刚 建立
stationary a nice robot arm let's say
固定一个漂亮的机器人手臂让我们说
you know a standard industrial arm and
你知道一个标准的工业臂和
it can wash the ball come and then swing
它可以洗球来然后摆动
the racket it's a good question I'm not
球拍这是一个很好的问题， 我 不是
sure it would be super hard to do I mean
我的意思是，这确实很难
I'm sure it would require a lot if we do
如果我们这样做，我相信它会需要很多
it breed with reinforced Maleny would
它与强壮的马勒尼一起繁殖
require a lot of trial and error it's
需要进行大量的试验和 错误是
not gonna swing it right the first time
第一次不会正确摆动它
around but yeah I don't I don't see why
周围但我是不是我不明白 为什么
I couldn't see the right way I think
我想不出正确的方式
it's learn about I think if you set up a
它会了解我认为如果你设置了一个
ball machine let's say on one side and
球机让我们说一边和
then a robot with a tennis racket on the
然后是一个带网球拍的机器人
other side
另一边
I think it's learn about and maybe a
我认为它是学习的，也许是一个
little bit of pre training and
一点点的预训练和
simulation yeah I think that's I think
模拟是啊我 想我 认为
that's feasible I think I think the
这是可行的 我认为我认为
swinging the racket is feasible I'd be
摆动球拍是 可行的
very interesting to see how much
非常有趣， 看 多少
precision it can get
它可以获得精确度
listen I mean that's that's where I mean
听我的意思是那就是我的意思
some of the human players can hit it on
一些人类玩家可以打它
the lines which is very high precision
精度非常高 的线条
with spin this win is it is an
旋转这个 胜利 是一个
interesting whether RL can learn to put
很有意思RL 是否 可以学会放
a spin on the ball well you got me
很好地旋转球 你得到了我
interested maybe someday we'll set this
感兴趣也许 有一天我们会设置这个
is your answer is basically okay for
你的答案基本上 没问题
this problem it sounds fascinating but
这个问题听起来很迷人但是
for the general problem of a tennis
对于网球的一般问题
player we might be a little bit farther
球员我们可能会 更远一点
away what's the most impressive thing
离开什么是最令人印象深刻的事情
you've seen a robot do in the physical
你见过一个机器人做的物理
world so physically for me it's the
这个世界 对我来说真的很棒
Boston Dynamics videos always just ring
波士顿动力学视频总是响起
home and just super impressed
家里只是超级印象深刻
recently the robot running up the stairs
最近机器人跑上楼梯
doing the parkour type thing
做跑酷式的东西
I mean yes we don't know what's
我的意思是， 我们不知道是什么
underneath they don't really write a lot
他们下面并没有写很多东西
of detail but even if it's hard coded
细节但即使它是硬 编码的
underneath which you might or might not
你可能会或可能 不会
be just the physical abilities of doing
只是做的身体能力
that parkour that's a very impressive so
那跑酷，这是一个非常令人印象深刻，从而
a lot right there have you met spot many
很多，你见过很多
or any of those robots in person might
或任何这些 机器人 可能
spot mini last hearing in April at the
现场迷你 4月份的 最后一次 听证会
Mars event that Jeff Bezos organizes
杰夫贝索斯组织的火星事件
they brought it out there and it was
他们带来了它，它是
nicely falling around Jeff when Jeff
杰夫 ，杰夫，很好地摔倒了杰夫
left the room they had it
离开他们拥有它的房间
follow him along which is pretty
跟着他走的很漂亮
impressive so I think there's some
令人印象深刻 所以我认为有一些
confidence to know that there's no
有信心知道 没有
learning going on in those robots the
在那些机器人中 继续 学习
psychology of it so while knowing that
知道这一点的心理学
while knowing there's not if there's any
虽然知道没有，如果有的话
learning going on it's very limited
继续学习是非常有限的
I met spot Minnie earlier this year and
我遇到了今年现货米妮更早
knowing everything that's going on
了解正在发生的一切
having one-on-one interaction so I got
我得到了一对一的互动
to spend some time alone and there's a
花一些时间独自一人，有一个
immediately a deep connection on the
马上就有了深刻的联系
psychological level even though you know
心理水平，即使你知道
the fundamentals how it works there's
它的基本原理是如何运作的
something magical so do you think about
神奇的东西所以你认为
the psychology of interacting with
与之 交互的 心理
robots in the physical world even you
物理世界中的机器人甚至是你
just showed me the pr2 the the robot and
只是告诉我 pr2机器人和
and there was a little bit something
并有一点点 东西
like a face head a little bit something
像一个脸部头部 有点东西
like a face there's something that
就像一张脸，有一些东西
immediately draws you to it do you think
你认为 立即吸引你
about that aspect of
关于 那个方面
of the robotics problem well it's very
机器人问题以及它是 非常
hard with bread here we'll give him a
在这里，面包很难， 我们会给他一个
name Berkeley robot for the elimination
命名伯克利机器人 以消除
of tedious tasks is very hard to not
繁琐的任务 很难做到
think of the robot as a person and it
把机器人想象成一个人和它
seems like everybody calls him a he for
似乎每个人都称他为他
whatever reason but that also makes it
无论什么原因，但也成功
more a person than if it was a it and
一个人比一个人更多
it's it seems pretty natural to think of
想起来似乎很自然
it that way this past weekend really
这就是上周末真的这样
struck me I've seen pepper many times on
忽然想起我见过辣椒很多次上
on videos but then I was at an event
在视频上然后我参加了一个活动
organized by this was by fidelity and
由此组织的是忠诚 和
they had scripted pepper to help
他们用胡椒粉 来帮忙
moderate some sessions and yet scripted
适度的一些会议 ，但脚本
pepper to have the personality of a
辣椒具有的个性
child a little bit and it was very hard
孩子一 点点，这很难
to not think of it as its own person in
不要把 它当作自己的人
some sense because it was just kind of
某种意义，因为它只是一种
jumping it would just jump into
跳它会跳进去
conversation making it very interactive
谈话使它非常互动
moderate will be saying pepper just jump
温和的会说辣椒 只是 跳
in hold on how about me can I
在保持上我怎么办 我 能
participate in this doing it just like I
参与这个就像我一样
heard this is like like a person and I
听说这就像一个人和我
was 100% scripted and even then it was
为 100％照本宣科，甚至然后它是
hard not to have that sense of somehow
很难不要有某种感觉
there is something there so as we have
就像我们一样，有一些东西
robots interact in this physical world
机器人在这个物理世界中互动
is that a signal that can be used in
是一个 可 用于 的信号
reinforcement learning you've you've
强化学习你就是你
worked a little bit in this direction
在这方面做了一点点工作
but do you think that's that psychology
但你认为这就是心理学吗？
can be somehow pulled in now so that's a
现在可以以某种方式拉入，这样就可以了
question
题
I would say a lot a lot of people ask
我会说 很多 人都会问
and I think part of why they ask it is
而且我认为他们为什么会这样问的部分原因
they're thinking about how unique are we
他们在想我们有多 独特
really still ask people like after they
真的还是会问人们喜欢他们之后
see some results they see a computer
看到一些他们看到电脑的结果
play go to say computer do this that
玩去说电脑这样做
they're like ok but can it really have
他们很好，但 真的 可以
emotion can it really interact with us
情感可以真正与我们互动
in that way and then once you're around
以这种方式，然后一旦你身边
robots you already start feeling it and
你已经开始感觉它的机器人和
I think that kind of maybe
我觉得那种 可能
mythologically the way that I think of
神话上我想到的方式
it is if you run something like
如果你运行的话就是这样
reinforce some Linux about optimizing
强化一些关于优化的Linux
some objective and there's no reason
一些目标，没有 理由
that D object couldn't be tied into how
该d对象无法被捆绑 到如何
much there's a person like interacting
很多人都喜欢互动
with this system and why could not the
用这个系统 ，为什么不能
reinforcement learning system optimized
强化学习系统优化
for their robot being fun to be around
他们的机器人是乐趣 左右
and
和
why wouldn't it then naturally become
为什么它不会自然而然地成为
more and more interactive and more and
越来越多的 互动和更多
more maybe like a person or like a pet I
更多可能像一个人或像宠物一样
don't know what it would exactly be but
不知道它究竟是什么但是
more more have those features and
更多有这些功能和
acquire them automatically as long as
只要自动获取它们
you can formalize an objective of what
你可以正式确定目标
it means to like something what how you
它意味着要喜欢你的方式
exhibit what's the ground truth how do
展示什么是基本事实怎么做
you how do you get the reward from human
你怎么做你从人的奖励
cause you have to somehow collect that
因为你 必须以某种方式收集它
information within you human
你人类内部的信息
but you you're saying if you can
但是你说你是否可以
formulate as an objective it can be
它可以作为一个目标
learned there is no reason it couldn't
据悉，没有理由不能
emergent through learning and maybe one
通过学习突然出现，也许是一个
way to formulate has an objective you
制定方式有客观的你
wouldn't have to necessarily score it
不一定要得分
explicitly so standard rewards are
明确如此标准的奖励
numbers and numbers are hard to come by
数字和数字很难得到
this is a 1.5 or 0.7 on some scale it's
这 是 一些规模是 1.5或 0.7
very hard to do for a person but much
很难为一个人做 很多事情
easier is for a person to say okay what
容易是一个 人 说 什么没关系
you did the last five minutes was much
你最后 五 分钟做的很多
nicer than we did the previous five
比我们之前的五个更好
minutes and that now gives a comparison
分钟， 现在 给出了比较
compare and in fact there have been some
比较 ，实际上有 一些
results in that for example Paul
导致例如保罗
Christiana and collaborators at open e I
克里斯蒂安娜和开放的合作者我
had the hopper madoka Hopper one legged
料斗madoka Hopper 单腿
robot the Batman's little back flips
机器人蝙蝠侠的 小 背部翻转
yeah purely from feedback I like this
是的，纯粹来自反馈，我喜欢这个
better than that that's kind of equally
比 那种平等更好
good and after a bunch of interactions
很好，经过一堆互动
it figured out what it was the person
它弄明白这是什么人
was asking for it namely a back flip and
要求它 是一个 后翻和
so I think the same thing
所以我想同样的事情
od wasn't trying to do a back flip it
od 并没有试图做后背 翻转它
was just getting a score from the
才刚刚从一分
comparison score from the person based
来自人的比较得分
on hers and having a mind in their own
在她 自己和自己心中
mind what I wanted to do a back flip but
记住我想要做什么后翻
the robot didn't know what it was
机器人不知道它是什么
supposed to be doing it just knew that
应该这样做只是知道
sometimes the person said this is better
有时这个人说这更好
this is worse and then the robot figure
这 更糟糕 ，然后机器人的 形象
it out what the person was actually
这个 人 实际上是 什么
after was a back flip and I'd imagine
之后是一个后空翻和 我 想像
the same would be true for things like
对于类似的事情也是如此
more interactive robots that the robot
更具互动性的机器人即机器人
would figure out over time oh this kind
会想出这种随着时间的推移哦
of thing apparently has appreciated more
事情显然 已经升值了
than this other kind of thing so when I
比起这种其他 的事情，所以当我
first picked up
先拿起来
Sutton's Richard Sutton's reinforcement
萨顿的理查德萨顿的强化
learning book before sort of this deep
在这种深刻的学习之前
learning before the re-emergence of
在 重新出现 之前学习
neural networks is a powerful mechanism
神经网络是一种强大的机制
for machine learning IRL seemed to me
机器学习 IRL似乎对我而言
like magic as a as beautiful so
像魔法一样美丽如此
that seemed like what intelligence is RL
这似乎 是RL的智慧
reinforcement learning so how do you
强化学习你怎么样
think we can possibly learn anything
我想我们可以学到任何东西
about the world when the reward for the
关于世界 的时候奖励 了
actions is delayed is so sparse like
被延迟的行动是如此稀疏的像
where is why do you think RL works why
为什么你认为RL的原因在哪里？
do you think you can learn anything
你认为你可以学到什么吗？
under such sparse awards whether it's
在这样稀疏的 奖项下是否是
regular reinforcement learning a deeper
定期强化学习更深入
enforcement learning what's your
执法学习什么是你的
intuition the kind of part of that is
直觉就是那种 方式
why is RL why does it need so many
为什么RL 为什么需要这么多
samples so many experiences to learn
抽样学习这么多经验
from because really what's happening is
从因为真正发生的事情是
when you have a sparse reward you do
当你获得稀疏奖励时
something maybe for like I don't know
东西也许像 我不 知道
you take a hundred actions and then you
你采取了一百个 行动，然后你
get a reward and maybe get like a score
获得 奖励， 也许得到一个分数
of three and I'm like okay three not
三个，我 很好，三个 不是
sure what that means you go again and
确定这 意味着你再去一次
now I get to and now you know that that
现在我到了，现在你知道了
sequence of hundred actions that you did
你做过 的 一百个动作的顺序
the second time around somehow was worse
第二次以某种方式更糟糕
than the sequence of hundred actions you
比你一百个行动的顺序
did the first time around but that's
第一次做了，但那是
tough to now know which one of those
现在很难知道哪一个
were better or worse some might have
有些人可能 有 更好或更差
been good and bad in either one and so
在任何一方都是好的和坏的
that's why I need so many experience but
这就是我需要这么多经验的原因
once you have enough experiences
一旦你有足够的经验
effectively rlist easing that apart it's
有效地推动缓和它的区别
time to say okay when what is
什么是时候说好的
consistently there when you get a higher
当你获得更高的时候，始终存在
reward and what's consistently there
奖励和一直在那里
when you get a lower reward and then
当你获得较低的奖励 然后
kind of the magic of sums is the policy
善意的一种魔力就是政策
grant update is to say
授予更新就是说
now let's update the neural network to
现在让我们更新神经网络
make the actions that were kind of
做出 那种行为
present when things are good more likely
在场的时候东西是好的可能性更大
and make the actions that are present
并做出存在的行动
when things are not as good less likely
当事情不那么好的可能性
so that's that is the counterpoint but
所以那就是对位但是
it seems like you would need to run it a
好像你需要运行它
lot more than you do even though right
即使是正确的，也比你做得多
now people could say that RL is very
现在 人们可以说RL非常
inefficient but it seems to be way more
效率低但似乎 更多
efficient than one would imagine on
比人们想象的更有效率
paper that the the simple updates to the
论文即简单更新了
policy the policy gradient that that's
政策政策梯度那是
somehow you can learn is exactly users
不知怎的， 你可以学习的确是 用户
said what are the common actions that
说什么是共同的行动
seem to produce some good results that
似乎产生了一些好的结果
that somehow can learn anything it seems
以某种方式 可以学到任何东西
counterintuitive at least did is there
反直觉，至少确实存在
some intuition behind yeah so I think
我认为背后有些直觉
there's a few ways to think about this
有几种方法可以 考虑这一点
the way I Tennant
我 Tennant的方式
about it mostly originally when so when
关于它大多是最初的时候
we started working on deep reinforcement
我们开始致力于深层加固
learning here at Berkeley which was
在伯克利学习，这是
maybe two thousand eleven twelve
也许是二千一十一
thirteen around that time
那个时候十三岁左右
challenge Schulman was a PhD student
挑战Schulman 是一名博士生
initially kind of driving it too forward
最初有点推动它 前进
here and did it the way we thought about
在这里 ， 按照我们想到的方式做到了
it at the time was if you think about
它当时是你想的
rectified linear units or kind of break
整流线性单元或断裂类型
the fire type neural networks what do
火型神经网络做什么
you get you get something that's
你能得到一些东西
piecewise linear feedback control and if
分段线性反馈控制和if
you look at the literature linear
你看文献线性
feedback control is extremely successful
反馈控制非常成功
can solve many many problems
可以解决很多问题
surprisingly well
出乎意料的好
I remember for example when we did
我记得比如我们 做的时候
helicopter flight if you're in a
直升机飞行，如果你在
stationary flight regime not a non
固定飞行制度不是 非
station by the stationary flight regime
站在固定飞行机制
like hover you can use linear feedback
像悬停一样，你可以使用线性反馈
control to stabilize a helicopter a very
控制稳定一架直升机
complex dynamical system but the
复杂的动力系统但是
controller is relatively simple and so I
控制器比较简单 ，所以我
think that's a big part of is that if
认为这是一个大的一部分 是 ，如果
you do feedback control even though the
你这样做， 即使反馈控制
system you control can be very very
你控制的系统可以非常非常
complex often relatively simple control
复杂的往往控制比较简单
architectures can already do a lot but
架构已经可以做很多了
then also just linear is not good enough
然后也只是线性不够好
and so one way you can think of these
所以你可以想到 这些
neural networks is that in sometimes
神经网络 有时 就是这样
they tile the space which people were
他们平铺了人们所处的空间
already trying to do more by hand or
已经尝试用手或手做更多
with finite state machines say this
有限 状态机 说这个
linear controller here this leaner
线性控制器在这里更精简
controller here you'll network learns
控制器在这里你会网络学习
that alva spins a linear controller here
alva在这里旋转一个线性控制器
another linear controller here but it's
另一个线性控制器，但它是
more subtle than that yeah and so it's
比那更微妙，所以它是
benefiting from this linear control
受益于这种线性控制
aspect is benefiting from the tiling but
方面受益于平铺但是
it's somehow tiling it one dimension at
它以某种方式平铺它的一个维度
a time because if let's say you have a
一段时间， 因为 如果让我们说 你有一个
two layer network even the hidden layer
两层网络 甚至是隐藏层
you make a transition from active to
你从活跃转变为
inactive or the other way around that is
不活动或 周围 的 其他方式
essentially one axis but not acts as a
基本上是一个轴， 但不作为一个轴
line but one direction that you change
行，但你改变了一个方向
and so you have this kind of very
所以你有这样的 非常
gradual tiling of the space we have a
我们有 一个 空间的逐渐平铺
lot of sharing between the linear
很多线性之间的共享
controllers that tile the space and that
控制器， 平铺空间和
was always my intuition s of why to
总是我直觉的原因
expect that this might work pretty well
期望这可能会 很好
it's essentially leveraging the fact
它基本上是利用这个事实
that linear feedback control is so good
线性反馈控制 非常好
but of course not enough and this is a
但当然不够，这是一个
gradual tiling of the space with linear
用线性逐渐平铺 空间
feedback controls that share a lot of
反馈控制分享了很多
expertise across them so that that's
碰到他们的专业知识， 使这
that's really nice intuition do you
你 真的很直觉 吗？
think that scales to the more and more
认为规模越来越大
general problems of when you start going
你开始去的 一般问题
up the number of controllers dimensions
增加控制器尺寸的数量
when you start going down in terms of
当你开始 下降时
how often you get a clean reward signal
你多久得到一个清晰的奖励信号
does that intuition carry forward to
这种直觉是否会延续下去
those crazy or weird or worlds that we
那些疯狂或奇怪 或 世界的我们
think of as the real world so I think
我认为这就是现实世界
where things get really tricky in the
事情变得在真正棘手
real world compared to the things we've
现实世界与我们所拥有的东西相比
looked at so far with great success in
到目前为止看起来非常成功
reinforcement learning is
强化学习是
the time skills which takes us to an
把我们带到 的时间技巧
extreme so when you think about the real
当你想到真实的时候，这是极端的
world I mean I don't know maybe some
世界我的意思是我不知道也许一些
student decided to do a a PhD here right
学生决定在这里做博士
okay that's that's the decision that's a
好吧 那就是那个决定
very high-level decision but if you
非常高层的决定，但如果你
think about their lives I mean any
想想他们的生活我的意思是 任何
person's life it's a sequence of muscle
人的生命是一系列肌肉
fiber contractions and relaxations and
纤维收缩和放松和
that's how you interact with the world
这就是你与世界互动的方式
and that's a very high frequency control
这是一个 非常高频率的控制
thing but it's ultimately what you do
事情，但它最终是你做的
and how you affect the world until I
以及你如何影响世界直到 我
guess we have brain readings and you can
猜猜我们有脑部读数， 你可以
maybe do it slightly differently but
也许做的略有不同 但是
typically that's how you affect the
通常这就是你如何 影响
world and the decision of doing a PhD is
世界和 做博士 的决定 是
like so abstract relative to what you're
就像你所说的那样抽象
actually doing in the world and I think
实际上在世界上做，我 想
that's where credit assignment becomes
这就是信用分配的地方
just completely beyond what any current
完全超越任何潮流
RL algorithm can do and we need
RL算法可以做到而且我们需要
hierarchical reasoning at a level that
在一个水平层次推理
is just not available at all yet where
根本没有 可用的 地方
do you think we can pick up hierarchical
你认为我们可以采取等级制度
reasoning by which mechanisms yeah so
推理机制是这样的
maybe let me highlight what I think the
也许让我突出我的想法
limitations are of what already was done
已经完成的限制
20-30 years ago in fact you'll find
事实上你会发现 20  -  30 年前
reasoning systems that reason over
推理系统推理
relatively long horizons but the
相对较长的视野但是
problems that they were not grounded in
他们 没有在接地的 问题
the real world so people would have to
现实世界，人们将不得不这样 做
hand design some kind of logical
手工设计某种逻辑
dynamical descriptions of the world and
对世界 和 世界的动态描述
that didn't tie into perception and so
这并没有与 感知 联系在一起
then time to real objects and so forth
然后到真实物体的时间等等
and so that that was a big gap now with
所以现在 这 是一个很大的差距
deep learning we start having the
深度学习我们开始 具有
ability to really see with sensors
能够真正看到传感器
process that and understand what's in
处理并理解其中的内容
the world and so it's a good time to try
世界，所以这是一个尝试的好时机
to bring these things together one I see
我把这些东西放在一起
a few ways of getting there one way to
通过一种方式到达那里的几种方法
get there would be to say deep learning
到那里会说深刻的学习
can get bolted on somehow to some of
可以用某种方式用螺栓固定
these more traditional approaches now
现在这些更传统的方法
bolted on would probably mean you need
用螺栓固定可能意味着你需要
to do some kind of end-to-end training
做一些端到端的培训
where you say my deep learning
你说我深入学习的地方
processing somehow leads to a
处理以某种方式导致a
representation that in Perm uses some
表示 ，其在 烫发使用一些
kind of traditional underlying dynamical
一种传统的潜在动力
systems that can be used for planning
可用于规划的系统
and that's for example the direction
这就是方向
Aviv Tamar and the North Korea touch
Aviv Tamar和朝鲜触摸
here have been pushing with causal info
这里一直在推动因果信息
gone and of course other people to that
走了，当然还有其他人 说
that's that's one way can we somehow
那是我们的某种方式
force it into the form factor that is
迫使它变成是外形
amenable to reasoning
适合推理
another direction we've been thinking
我们一直在思考的另一个方向
about for a long time and they didn't
约长一段时间，他们没有
make any progress on was more
取得任何进展更多
information theoretic approaches so the
信息理论方法所以
idea there was that what it means to
知道有这 意味着什么？
take high-level action is to take and
采取高层行动是采取和
choose a latent variable now that tells
选择一个潜变量， 现在 告诉
you a lot about what's gonna be the case
你会了解很多情况
in the future because that's what it
在未来， 因为它 就是它
means to to take a high-level action I
意味着采取高级别的行动我
say what I decide I'm gonna navigate to
说 什么我决定我要 定位到
the gas station because need to get gas
加油站因为需要加油
for my car well that'll now take five
对于我的车来说，现在需要五个
minutes to get there but the fact that I
分钟到那里，但事实 证明 我
get there I could already tell that from
得到那里， 我已经可以告诉大家， 从
the high-level action it took much
它 采取 的高级别 行动 很多
earlier that we had a very hard time
早些时候我们 很难过
getting success with not saying it's a
获得成功而不是说它是一个
dead-end necessarily but we had a lot of
死胡同必定但我们有很多
trouble getting that to work and then we
难以让它工作 ，然后 我们
start revisiting the notion of what are
开始重新审视什么是概念
we really trying to achieve what we're
我们真的想要 实现 我们的目标
trying to achieve is non ously hierarchy
试图实现的 是非等级的
per se but you could think about what
本身但你可以考虑一下
does hierarchy give us what it's we hope
层次结构给我们带来了我们希望的东西
it would give us is better credit
它会给我们更好的信誉
assignment kind of what is better credit
任务类型 什么是更好的信用
ominous is given is giving us it gives
给予我们 给予的 不祥之处
us faster learning right and so faster
我们更快地学习，更快
learning is ultimately maybe what we're
学习是 最终也许就是我们
after and so that's what we ended up
之后，这就是我们最终的结果
with the RL squared paper on learning -
学习RL平方纸 -
reinforcement learn which at a time
加强一次学习哪些
rocky duan LED and that's exactly the
岩石段 LED，这正是
meta learning approach or is say okay we
元学习方法或者 说好的我们
don't know how to design hierarchy we
我不知道如何设计 层次结构
know what we want to get from it let's
知道我们想要从中得到 什么
just enter an optimize for what want to
只需输入 想要 的 优化
get from it and see if it might emerging
从中得到它，看看它是否会出现
we saw things emerge the maze navigation
我们看到东西出现了迷宫导航
had consistent motion down hallways
在走廊上有一致的动作
which is what you want a hierarchical
这是你想要的层次结构
control should say I want to go down
控制应该说我想要走下去
this hallway and then when there is an
这个走廊然后当有一个
option to take a turn I can this art
选择转弯 我可以这个艺术
will take a turn or not and repeat even
将转或不转，甚至重复
had the notion of where have you been
有你在哪里的概念
before or not do not revisit places
之前或不重新访问的 地方
you've been before it still didn't scale
你去过 它之前还没有扩展
yet to the real world kind of scenarios
但对于现实世界的场景
I think you had in mind but it was some
我想你有这个想法， 但它有些
sign of life that maybe you can meta
生命的迹象，也许你可以 元
learn these hierarchal concepts I mean
我的意思是学习这些层级概念
it seems like through these meta
似乎通过这些元
learning concepts get at the what I
学习概念得到我的意义
think is one of the
认为的一个
hardest and most important problems of
最难和最重要的问题
AI which is transfer learning so it's
AI是传输系统的学习，这是
generalization how far along this
概括多远沿着这
journey towards building general systems
建设一般系统的旅程
are we being able to do transfer
我们能够做转移吗？
learning well so there's some signs that
学得很好，所以有一些迹象表明
you can generalize a little bit but do
你可以概括一点，但做到
you think we're on the right path or
你认为我们正走在正确的道路上
it's totally different breakthroughs are
这是完全不同的 突破
needed to be able to transfer knowledge
需要能够转移知识
between different learned models yeah
不同的学习模型之间是啊
I'm I'm pretty tired on this and then I
我对此很累， 然后 我
think there are some very many there
认为那里有 很多
there's just some very impressive
只有一些非常令人印象深刻
results already right I mean yes I would
结果已经正确我的意思 是我会的
say when even with the initial and a big
甚至在初始和大的时候说
breakthrough in 2012 with Aleks net
Aleks net在2012年取得突破
right the initial the initial thing is
最初的 事情是最初的
okay great this does better on imagenet
好的，这在imagenet上做得更好
hands image recognition but then
然后手上的图像识别
immediately thereafter that was of
此后立即出现
course the notion that Wow
当然 是哇 的 想法
what was learned on image net and you
在图像网和你学到了什么
now want to solve a new task you can
现在想要解决一项新任务
fine-tune Aleks net for new tasks and
为新任务微调Aleks网络
that was often found to be the even
这经常被发现是偶数
bigger deal that you learned something
你学到了什么更重要的事情
that was reusable which was not often
这是可以重复使用的，而且不常见
the case before usually machine learning
通常在机器学习之前 的情况
you learned something for one scenario
你为一个场景学到了一些东西
and that was it and that's really
仅此而已 ，这就是真的
exciting I mean that's just a huge
令人兴奋我的意思是，这只是一个巨大的
application that's probably the biggest
应用这 可能 是 最大的
success of transfer learning today in
今天转学的成功
terms of scope and impact that was huge
范围和影响的范围 很大
breakthrough and then recently I feel
突破，然后最近 我觉得
like similar kind of but by scaling
喜欢类似但通过缩放
things up it seems like this has been
事情 似乎就是 这样
expanded upon like people training even
甚至像人们一样训练
bigger networks they might transfer even
他们甚至可能转移更大的网络
better if you looked at for example some
如果你看 一些 例子，那会更好
of the opening eye results on language
语言 开幕 眼睛结果
models and some of the recent Google
模特和一些最近的谷歌
results on language models they are
他们的语言模型的结果
learned for just prediction and then
学会了只是预测然后
they get reused for other tasks and so I
他们被重新用于其他任务，所以我
think there is something there where
认为那里有什么东西
somehow if you train a big enough model
不知何故， 如果你训练一个足够大的模型
on enough things it seems to transfer
在足够的事情似乎转移
some deepmind results I thought were
我认为是一些深刻的结果
very impressive unreal results where it
非常令人印象深刻的虚幻结果
was learned to navigate mazes in ways
学会了以某种方式导航迷宫
where it wasn't just
它不仅仅是
reinforcement learning going to have
强化学习将会有
other objectives was optimizing for so I
其他目标正在优化，所以我
think there's a lot of interesting
认为有很多有趣的东西
results already I think maybe words hard
我觉得结果已经很难了
to wrap my head around this to which
包裹我的头周围这 其中
extend or when do we call something
延伸或什么时候我们称之为
generalization right or the levels of
泛化权利或等级
generalization involved in these
涉及这些的概括
different tasks alright so you draw this
不同的任务 好吧，所以你画这个
by the way just to frame things you've
顺便说一句， 只是 为了框架 你的 东西
heard you say somewhere it's the
听说你说某个地方就是这样
difference between learning to master
学习掌握 之间的区别
versus learning to generalize that it's
而不是学习 如何概括 它
a nice line to think about and it guess
一个很好的思考方式，它猜测
you're saying that's a gray area of what
你说这 是 什么 的灰色 区域
learning to master and learning to
学会掌握和学习
generalize where once think I might have
概括在 曾经认为我可能拥有的地方
heard this I might have heard it
听到这 我可能 已经听说过它
somewhere else and I think it might have
在其他地方，我认为它可能有
been one of one of your interviews and
是你 的 采访 中之一 ，
maybe the one with yo show Benjamin on
也许那个与你展示本杰明的人
hundred percent sure but I like the
百分百肯定， 但我喜欢
example I'm gonna act not sure who it
例如，我会不确定是谁
was but the example was essentially if
但实例基本上就是这样
you use current deep learning techniques
你使用当前的深度学习技巧
what we're doing to predict let's say
我们正在做什么来预测让我们说
the relative motion of our planets it
我们行星的相对运动 吧
would do pretty well but then now if a
会做得很好， 但 现在如果一个
massive new mass enters our solar system
巨大的新质量进入我们的太阳系
it would prompt predict what will happen
它会提示预测会发生什么
right and that's a different kind of
对，那是另一种
journal is a Shahnaz a generalization
期刊是Shahnaz的一个 概括
that relies on the ultimate simplest
这取决于最简单的
simplest explanation that we have
我们有最简单的解释
available today to explain the motion of
目前可用 来 解释的议案
planets where I was just pattern
我只是 模式的 行星
recognition could predict our current
认可可以预测我们的当前
solar system motion pretty well no
太阳系运动相当不行
problem and so I think that's an example
问题，所以我认为这是一个 例子
of a kind of generalization that is a
作为一种概括的一种
little different from what we've
与我们的一点点不同
achieved so far and it's not clear if
到目前为止已达到目前尚不清楚
just you know regularizing more I'm
只是你知道 我 更多的正规化
forcing it to come up with a simpler
迫使其拿出 一个更简单
simpler simple experience but it's not
更简单的经验， 但事实并非如此
simple but that's what physics
简单，但这 就是物理学
researchers do right to say can I make
研究者们说得对，我可以做
this even simpler how simple can I get
这更简单，我能得到多么简单
this what's a simplest equation I can
这是 我能做 的 最简单的方程式
explain everything right yeah the master
解释一切正确是的主人
equation for the entire dynamics of the
方程的整个动态
universe we haven't really pushed that
宇宙我们还没有真正推动它
direction as hard in in deep learning I
在深度学习中努力的方向我
would say not sure if it should be
要说不知道是否 应该
pushed but it seems a kind of
推，但似乎是一种
generalization you get from that that
你从中得到的概括
you don't get in our current methods
你 没有进入我们目前的方法
so far so I just talked to vladimir
到目前为止，我刚刚和弗拉基米尔谈过
vapnik for example who was a
Vapnik等，例如谁是
statistician the statistical learning
统计学家统计学习
and he kind of dreams of creating these
他有点想创造 这些
are the a equals e equals mc-squared for
等于e等于mc平方
learning right the general theory of
学习权的一般理论
learning do you think that's a fruitless
学习你认为那是徒劳的
pursuit in the near term in within the
追求 中 短期 的
next several decades I think that's a
接下来的几十年， 我认为这是一个
really interesting pursuit and in the
真正有趣的追求和在
following sense and that there is a lot
跟随感觉并且有很多
of evidence that the brain is pretty
证据表明大脑很漂亮
modular and so I wouldn't maybe think of
模块化，所以我不会想到
it as the theory maybe the the
它可能就像理论一样
underlying theory but more kind of the
潜在的理论，但更多的
principle where there have been findings
有发现的原则
where people who are blind will use the
盲人的人会使用
part of the brain usually used for
通常用于大脑的一部分
vision for other functions and even
对其他功能的愿景甚至是
after some kind of if people will get
经过某种程度的 人们会得到
rewired in some way they might I'm able
以某种方式重新布线他们可能我 能够
to reuse parts of their brain for other
为他人重用大脑的一部分
functions and so what that suggests is
功能，所以这意味着什么
some kind of modularity and I think it
某种模块化，我认为
is a pretty natural thing to strive
努力是很自然的事情
forward to see can we find that
我们 可以找到它
modularity can we find this thing of
模块化我们可以发现这个 东西
course it's not every part of the brain
当然， 这不是 大脑的 每一个部分
is not exactly the same not everything
并非完全相同而 不是一切
can be rewired arbitrarily but if you
可以任意重新布线，但如果你
think of things like the neocortex which
想想像 新皮质这样的东西
is pretty big part of the brain that
是大脑的重要组成部分
seems fairly modular from what the
看起来相当模块化
findings so far can you design something
到目前为止你可以设计 一些东西
equally modular and if you can just grow
同样模块化，如果你可以成长
it it becomes more capable probably I
它可能我变得更有能力
think that would be the kind of
认为那将是 那种
interesting underlying principle to
有趣的基本原则
shoot for that is not unrealistic do you
为你拍摄并不是不现实的
think you prefer math or empirical trial
认为你更喜欢数学或实证 试验
and error for the discovery of the
发现的 错误
essence of what it means to do something
做某事的意义的本质
intelligent
智能
so reinforcement learning embodies both
所以强化学习体现了两者
groups right then prove that something
然后团体证明了这一点
converges prove the bounds and then at
收敛证明了界限，然后是
the same time a lot of those successes
同时 取得 了很多 成功
are well let's try this and see if it
很好，让我们试试这个，看看它
works so which do you gravitate towards
工作，你倾向于哪些
how do you think of those two parts of
你怎么看待那两个部分
your brain so
你的大脑如此
maybe I would prefer we could make the
也许我更希望我们可以做到
progress with mathematics and the reason
数学的进步和原因
maybe I would prefer that is because
也许我更希望那是因为
because often if you have something you
因为你经常拥有 一些东西
can mathematically formalise you can
可以在数学上形式化你可以
leapfrog a lot of experimentation and
超越了大量的实验和经验
experimentation takes a long time to get
实验需要很长时间才能得到
through and a lot of trial and error
通过和大量的反复试验
kind of reinforcement learning your
加强学习你的
research process but you need to do a
研究过程但你需要做一个
lot of trial and error before you get to
在 你到达 之前有很多反复试验
a success so if we can leapfrog doubt in
如果我们能够超越怀疑就成功了
my mind that's what the math is about
我的脑海里是这样的数学是什么
and hopefully once you do a bunch of
并希望一旦你做了一堆
experiments you start seeing a pattern
实验你开始看到一个 模式
you can do some derivations that
你可以做一些推导是
leapfrog some experiments but I agree
跳过一些实验，但我同意
with you I mean in practice a lot of the
和你在一起我的 意思是在实践中很多
progress has been such that we have not
进展一直 这样，我们 有 没有
been able to find the math that allows
能够找到 允许的数学
it to leapfrog ahead and we are kind of
它向前跨越，我们是一种
making gradual progress one step at a
逐步向前迈进一步
time a new experiment here a new
时间新的实验在这里一个新的
experiment there that gives us new
那里的实验给了我们新的
insights and gradually building up but
洞见并逐渐建立起来但是
not getting to something yet where we're
没有得到的 东西却在那里我们
just okay here's an equation that now
好的，这 是现在 的等式
explains how you know that would be have
解释你如何知道将有
been two years of experimentation to get
已经 有两年 的实验 获得
there but this tells us what the results
但这会告诉我们结果如何
going to be unfortunately not so much
遗憾的是没那么多
yes not so much yeah but your hope is
是的， 不是 很多，但是你的希望是
there in trying to teach robots or
那里试图教机器人或
systems to do everyday tasks or even in
系统可以完成日常任务甚至是日常任务
simulation what what do you think you're
模拟你认为你是什么
more excited about imitation learning or
对模仿 学习更感兴趣
self play
自我发挥
so letting robots learn from humans or
所以让机器人向人类学习或学习
letting robots plan their own to try to
让机器人计划自己 尝试
figure out in their own way and
以自己的方式弄清楚
eventually play eventually interact with
最终玩最终与之互动
humans or to solve whatever problem is
人类或解决任何问题
what's the more exciting to you what's
什么是更令你兴奋的是什么
more promising you think as a research
你认为更有前途的研究
direction so when we look at self play
因此，当我们看自我发挥
what's so beautiful about it is goes
什么是如此美丽它是 去
back to kind of the challenges in
回到那种挑战中
reinforcement learning so the challenge
强化学习所以挑战
of reinforced learning is getting signal
强化学习正在获得信号
and if you don't never succeed you don't
如果你永远不会成功， 你就不会
get any signal in self play you're on
在你自己的游戏中获得任何信号
both sides so one of you succeeds and
双方因此 你们中的 一个 成功 ，
the beauty is also one of you fails and
美丽也是 你失败的原因 之一
so you see the contrast you see the one
所以你看到的对比度，你看到一个
version of me that it better
它的版本，它更好
the other version and so every time you
每次你都是另一个版本
play yourself you get signal and so
发挥自己， 你得到信号等等
whenever you can turn something into
什么时候你可以把东西 变成
self play you're in a beautiful
自我发挥你在美丽
situation where you can naturally learn
你可以自然学习的情况
much more quickly than in most other
比 其他 大多数人快得多
reinforced learning environments so I
加强了学习环境， 所以我
think I think if somehow we can turn
我想如果我们能以某种方式转向
more reinforcement learning problems
更多强化学习问题
into self play formulations that would
为自我发挥制剂， 其会
go real really far so far south play has
真实到目前为止南方戏剧真的很远
been largely around games where there is
主要围绕着有游戏的游戏
natural opponents but if we could do
自然的对手，但如果我们能做到的话
self play if for other things and let's
如果为了其他事情而自我发挥，让我们
say I don't know a robot learns to build
说我不知道机器人学会建造
a house I mean that's a pretty advanced
我认为这是一个 非常先进的房子
thing to try to do for a robot but maybe
尝试为机器人做的事情但也许
it tries to build a hut or something if
它试图建立一个小屋或其他东西
that can be done through self play it
这可以 通过自我发挥 来 完成
would learn a lot more quickly if
如果能够更快地学到很多东西
somebody can figure that out and I think
有人能明白这 一点，我想
that would be something where it goes
这将成为 它的发展方向
closer to kind of the mathematical leap
更接近于数学上的飞跃
frogging where somebody figures out a
有人想出来的人
formalism to it's okay
形式主义对它没关系
any RL problem by playing this and this
玩这个和 这个 任何RL问题
idea you can turn it into a self play
想法你可以 把它变成一个自我发挥
problem where you get signal a lot more
你得到更多信号的问题
easily
容易
reality is many problems we don't know
现实是我们不知道的 许多问题
how to turn the self lay and so either
如何打开 自我躺在所以 无论是
we need to provide detailed reward that
我们需要提供详细的奖励
doesn't just reward for achieving a goal
不只是奖励实现目标
but rewards for making progress and that
但对于进取和奖励
becomes time-consuming and once you're
变得耗时，一旦你
starting to do that let's say you want a
开始做那个让我们说 你想要一个
robot to do something you need to give
机器人做你需要 给的 东西
all this detailed reward well why not
所有这些详细的奖励为什么不
just give a demonstration right because
只是举一个示威， 因为
why not just show the robot and now the
为什么不只是展示机器人，现在呢
question is how do you show the robot
问题是你如何展示机器人
one way to show is to tally operate the
展示的一种方式是统计操作
robot and then the robot really
机器人， 然后机器人真的
experiences things and that's nice
体验事物，这很好
because that's really high
因为那真的 很高
signal-to-noise ratio data and we've
我们已经知道了信噪比数据
done a lot of that and you teach your
做了很多，你教你的
robot skills in just 10 minutes you can
机器人技能只需 10分钟即可
teach your robot a new basic skill like
教你的机器人一个新的基本技能，如
okay pick up the bottle place it
还好 拿起 瓶子的地方它
somewhere else that's a skill no matter
在其他地方 ，无论如何都是技巧
where the bottle starts maybe it always
瓶子开始的地方也许总是如此
goes on to a target or something
接着的 目标什么的
that's fairly is a teacher about with
这相当是 一个 老师带左右
tally up now what's even more
现在计算得 更多了
interesting if you can now teach robot
有趣的是，你现在可以教机器人
through third person learning where the
通过第三人学习所在的地方
robot watches you do something and
机器人手表你做一些事情，
doesn't experience it but just watches
没有经历它，但 只是看着
it and says okay well if you're showing
如果你正在展示它并且说好的
me that that means I should be doing
我，那意味着我应该这样做
this and I'm not gonna be using your
这个，我不会 用你的
hand because I don't get to control your
一方面因为我没有得到控制你的
hand but I'm gonna use my hand I'd do
但是我会用我的手 做的
that mapping and so that's where I think
那个映射，所以这就是我的想法
one of the big breakthroughs has
其中一项重大突破
happened this year this was led by
发生在 今年， 这是由
Chelsea Finn here it's almost like
切尔西芬恩在这里几乎 就像
machine translation for demonstrations
演示机器翻译
were you have a human demonstration and
你有人类示威吗？
the robot learns to translated into what
机器人学会翻译成什么
it means for the robot to do it and that
它意味着机器人可以做到这一点
was a meta learning for a Malaysian
是对马来西亚人的元学习
learn from one to get the other and that
从中学习，以获得另一个和 那个
I think opens up a lot of opportunities
我 想开辟了很多 机会
to learn a lot more quickly so my focus
更 快速地 学到了很多 ，所以我的重点
is on autonomous vehicles do you think
你认为 是自动驾驶汽车 吗？
this approach of third-person watching
这种第三人 观看的方法
is about the autonomous driving is
是关于自动驾驶的
amenable to this a kind of approach so
这样做是一种方法
for autonomous driving I would say it's
对于自动驾驶我会说 是的
third-person is slightly easier and the
第三人是稍微容易 和
reason I'm gonna say slightly easier to
我会说 稍微容易一点的原因
do a third-person is because the hard
做第三人是因为努力
dynamics are very well understood so the
动力学是非常好理解的
easier than of first-person you mean or
比你的第一人称或者更容易
easier so I think the distinction
更容易，所以我认为区别
between third-person and first-person is
在第三人称和第一人称之间
not a very important distinction for
不是一个非常重要的区别
autonomous driving they're very similar
自动驾驶他们非常相似
because the distinction is really about
因为区别是真的
who turns the steering wheel and or
谁转动方向盘 和
maybe I'll let me put it differently how
也许我会让我用不同的方式
to get from a point where you are now to
从你现在的某个点开始
a point let's say a couple meters in
点假设 一对夫妇米
front of you and that's a problem that's
你的面前，这就是 这是 一个问题
very well understood and that's the only
非常了解，这是唯一的
distinction being third and first-person
区别是第三人和第一人
there whereas with the robot
那里有机器人
manipulation interaction forces are very
操纵互动力量非常大
complex and it's still a very different
复杂，它仍然是一个非常不同的
thing for autonomous driving I think
我认为自动驾驶的事情
there is still the question imitation
还有模仿的问题
versus RL so imitation gives you a lot
与RL相比，所以模仿给了你很多
more signal I think where imitation is
更多信号 我认为模仿的地方
lacking and needs some extra machinery
缺乏并需要一些额外的机器
is it doesn't in its normal format
是不是它的正常格式
doesn't think about goals or objectives
不考虑目标或目标
and of course there are versions of
当然也有版本 的
imitation learning inverse reinforce
模仿学习逆 加强
learning type imitation which also
学习 型的模仿也
thinks about goals I think then we're
思考我认为我们的目标
getting much closer but I think it's
越来越近，但 我认为是
very hard to think of a fully reactive
很难 想到 完全反应
car generalizing well if it really
汽车如果 真的 那么概括
doesn't have a notion of objectives to
没有目标的概念
generalize well to the kind of general
概括 为一般
that you would want you'd want more than
你想你想要超过
just that reactivity that you get from
只是 你得到的 反应
just behavioral cloning / supervised
只是行为克隆/监督
learning so a lot of the work whether
学习这么多 的工作是否如此
its self play
它的自我发挥
imitation learning would benefit
模仿学习会受益
significantly from simulation from
从模拟中显而易见
effective simulation and you're doing a
有效的模拟，你正在做一个
lot of stuff in the physical world and
物质 世界 中的很多东西
in simulation do you have hope for
在模拟中你有希望吗？
greater and greater power of simulation
越来越大的模拟能力
loop being boundless eventually to where
循环无边无际到了哪里
most of what we need to operate in the
我们需要在大部分时间内运作
physical world would could be simulated
可以模拟物理世界
to a degree that's directly transferable
达到可 直接转让 的程度
to the physical world are we still very
对于物质世界我们还是非常
far away from that so I think we could
远离那个，所以我想我们可以
even rephrase that question in some
甚至在某些方面重新提出这个问题
sense please so the power of simulation
请感觉仿真的力量
right simulators get better and better
正确的模拟器变得越来越好
of course become stronger and we can
当然会变得更强大，我们可以
learn more in simulation but there's
在模拟中学到更多，但有
also another version which is where you
也是你的另一个版本
said the simulator doesn't even have to
说模拟器甚至不必
be that precise as long as is somewhat
只要有点精确就是那么精确
representative and instead of trying to
代表而不是 试图
get one simulator that is sufficiently
得到一个足够的模拟器
precise to learn in and transfer really
准确地学习和转移真的
well to the real world
对现实世界而言
I'm gonna build many simulators ensemble
我要建立许多模拟器合奏
of simulators ensemble of simulators not
模拟器的集合模拟器没有
any single one of them is sufficiently
任何一个 都足够了
representative of the real world such
这样的现实代表
that it would work if you train in there
如果你在那里训练它会工作
but if you train in all of them then
但如果你在所有人中训练的话
there is something that's good in all of
有一些东西，在所有的好
them the real world will just be you
他们现实世界就是你
know another one that's you know cannot
知道另一个你不知道的人
identical to any one of them but just
与他们中的任何一个相同， 但 只是
another one of them another sample from
另一个 来自另一个样本
the distribution of simulators exact we
模拟器的分布非常 精确
do live in a simulation so this is just
生活在模拟中， 所以这只是
like oh one other one I'm not sure about
喜欢哦，另一个我 不确定
that video it's definitely a very
那个视频肯定是非常的
advanced simulator if it is yeah it's
先进的模拟器，如果是的话
pretty good one I've talked to this to
非常好的我已经跟这个谈过了
Russell is something you think about a
拉塞尔是你想想什么
little bit too of course you're like
你当然有点喜欢
really trying to build these systems but
真的想建立这些系统但是
do you think about the future of AI a
你觉得关于 AI的 未来
lot of people have concerned about
很多人都在关注
safety how do you think about AI safety
安全如何看待人身安全问题
as you build robots that are operating
当你建造 正在运行的 机器人时
in the physical world what what is uh
在物质世界中 ，什么是呃
yeah how do you approach this problem in
是的，你如何 接近这个问题
an engineering kind of way in a
工程学的一种方式
systematic way so what a robot is doing
系统的方式所以 机器人 在 做什么
things you
事情你
kind of have a few notions of safety to
有一些安全概念
worry about one is that Throwbot is
担心一个是Throwbot
physically strong and of course could do
身体强壮，当然可以
a lot of damage same for cars which we
对我们的汽车来说同样 的 损害很大
can think of as robots do in some way
可以想象机器人 以某种方式做
and this could be completely
这可能 是完全的
unintentional so it could be not the
无意中所以它可能不是
kind of long-term AI safety concerns
一种长期的 人工智能安全问题
that okay a is smarter than us and now
这样 行不行一个比 我们更聪明 ，现在
what do we do but it could be just very
我们做了什么，但它可能只是非常
practical okay this robot if it makes a
这个 机器人 实用还 可以
mistake
错误
whether the results going to be of
结果是否会成为
course simulation comes in a lot there
那里的课程模拟很多
too to test in simulation it's a
也可以在模拟中测试它是一个
difficult question and I'm always
困难的问题，我总是
wondering like I was wondering at let's
想知道我是在想我们
go back to drivings a lot of people know
回去驾驶 很多人都知道
driving well of course what do we do to
我们当然要做得 很好
test somebody for driving right to get a
测试某人驾驶得到权利
driver's license what do they really do
驾驶执照他们 真正做了什么
I mean you fill out some test and then
我的意思是你填写 一些测试 然后
you drive and I mean perfume in suburban
你开车，我指的是郊区的香水
California the driving test is just you
加州的驾驶考试 就是 你
drive around the block pull over you do
开车绕过你的地方
a stop sign successfully and then you
成功停止标志然后你
know you pull over again and you pretty
知道你 再次 拉 过来，你很漂亮
much done and you're like okay if a
做得很好，如果是的话，你会好起来的
self-driving car did dad would you trust
自驾车 做了爸爸，你会 信任
it that it can drive and be like no
它可以驱动，就像没有
that's not enough for me to trust but
这 对 我来说 还不够 信任
somehow for humans we've figured out
不知怎的，对于人类 我们已经想到了
that somebody being able to do that it's
有人能做到这一点
representative of them being able to do
代表他们能够 做到
a lot of other things and so I think
很多 其他的东西，所以我觉得
somehow for you must we figured out
不知何故，我们必须想出来
representative tests of what it means if
代表性的测试，如果
you can do this what you can really do
你可以做到这一点你真正能做到的
of course testing you must you must all
当然测试你必须你必须 所有
want to be tested at all times
希望在任何 时候 都 进行测试
self-driving cars the robots can be
机器人可以自动驾驶汽车
tested more often probably you can have
经常测试可能你可以拥有
replicas that get testament are known to
获得 遗嘱的复制品是众所周知的
be identical because they use the same
是相同的， 因为他们使用相同的
neural net and so forth but still I feel
神经网络 等等但我还是觉得
like we don't have this kind of unit
就像我们没有 这种 单位一样
tests or proper tests for for robots and
机器人和机器人的测试或适当的测试
I think there's something very
我觉得有一些非常
interesting to be thought about there
有趣的想到那里
especially as you update things your
特别是当你更新你的东西
software improves you have a better self
软件可以改善你拥有更好的自我
driving car suite you updated how do you
驾驶汽车套件你更新了你怎么样
know it's indeed more capable on
知道这是确实的更强大
everything than what you had before that
一切都比你之前的一切
you didn't have any bad things creep
你没有 任何坏事蔓延
into it so I think that's a very
进入它所以我认为这是非常的
interesting direction of research that
有趣 的研究方向
there is no real solution yet
还没有真正的解决方案
except that's somehow for you must we do
除了我们必须以某种方式完成
because we say okay you have a driving
因为我们说好的你有开车
test you passed you can go on the road
测试你通过你可以去 旅途中
now and you must have accents every like
现在，你必须有各自的口音
a million or ten million miles something
一百万或一千万英里的东西
something pretty phenomenal compared to
与...相比非常惊人的东西
that short test yeah that is being done
那个简短的测试是的，是的
so let me ask you've mentioned
所以让我问 你已经提到了
you mentioned that Andrew Aang by
你提到了Andrew Aang
example showed you the value of kindness
例子向你展示了仁慈的价值
and to do you think the space of
并且你认为的空间
policies good policies for humans and
政策良好的人类和政策
for AI is populated by policies that
对于AI，由政策填充
with kindness or ones that are the
善良或善良的
opposite exploitation even evil so if
反对剥削甚至邪恶如此
you just look at the sea of policies we
你只要看看我们的政策之海
operate under as human beings or if AI
在人类或人工智能下运作
system had to operate in this real world
系统必须在这个现实世界中运作
do you think it's really easy to find
你觉得它很容易找到吗？
policies that are full of kindness like
充满 善意的 政策
we naturally fall into them or is it
我们自然会陷入其中或是 它
like a very hard optimization problem I
像一个非常困难的优化问题我
mean there is kind of two optimizations
意味着有两种优化
happening for humans right so for you
正是为了你而发生的
most was kinda the very long-term
大多数是 有点 很 长远
optimization which evolution has done
进化所做的优化
for us and we're kind of predisposed to
对我们来说，我们有点倾向于
like certain things and that's in
喜欢某些东西，那就是
sometimes what makes our learning easier
有时候是什么让我们的学习更容
because I mean we know things like pain
因为我的意思是我们知道 痛苦之类的 事情
and hunger and thirst and the fact that
和饥饿和口渴以及事实
we know about those is not something
我们知道那些不是什么
that we were taught that's kind of
我们被教导的那种
innate when we're hungry were unhappy
我们饿的时候天生就不开心
when we're thirsty were unhappy when we
当我们口渴 时，我们不高兴
have pain we're unhappy and ultimately
有痛苦我们不开心，最终
evolution built that into us to think
进化建立在我们思考中
about this thing so so I think there is
关于 这个事情，所以让我 觉得有
a notion that it seems somehow humans
这似乎是人类的某种想法
evolved in general to prefer to get
一般来说进化到更喜欢得到
along in some ways but at the same time
在某些 方面，但在同一时间
also to be very territorial and kind of
也是非常领土和种类的
centric to their own tribe is it like it
为中心，以 自己的部落是它喜欢它
seems like that's the kind of space we
好像 这就是那种空间，我们的
converge down to it I mean I'm not an
收敛 到它我的意思是 我不是
expert in anthropology but it seems like
人类学专家， 但似乎
we're very kind of good within our own
我们很亲切在我们自己的好
tribe but need to be taught but to be
部落但需要 学习，但要
nice to other tribes well if you look at
如果你看一下，对其他部落很好
Steven Pinker he highlights is pretty
Steven Pinker他的亮点很漂亮
nicely in
很好地
better better angels of our nature where
更好的天使我们的天性
he talks about violence decreasing over
他谈到暴力减少
time consistently so whatever attention
时间一直如此无论如何注意
whatever teams we pick it seems that the
我们挑选的任何球队似乎都是
long arc of history goes towards us
历史的长期走向我们
getting along more and more so I hope so
相处越来越多 ，所以我希望如此
so do you think that do you think it's
所以你认为你认为是这样吗？
possible to cheat teach RL bass robots
可能作弊教RL低音机器人
the this kind of kindness this kind of
这种仁慈 这种
ability to interact with humans this
与人类这种交互的能力
kind of policy even - let me ask let me
甚至是一种政策- 让我问一下让我
ask a fun one do you think it's possible
问一个有趣的人你认为这是可能的吗？
to teach RL based robot to love a human
教RL基于机器人爱一个 人
being and to inspire that human to love
存在并 激励 人类去爱
the robot back so - like RL based
这样的机器人就像RL一样
algorithm that leads to a happy marriage
导致幸福婚姻的算法
that's interesting question maybe I'll
那个有趣的问题也许我会
oh I'll answer it with with another
哦，我会和另一个人一起回答
question right I mean it's it but I'll
问题是的，我的意思是它，但我会
come back to it so another question you
回到它，所以 另一个问题 你
can have is okay
可以是好的
I mean how close does some people's
我的意思是有些人有多近
happiness get from interacting with just
幸福来自与公正的互动
a really nice dog like I mean dogs you
一条非常好的狗，就像我的意思是狗
come home that's what dogs did they
回家就是狗狗做的事
greet you they're excited it makes you
迎接你， 他们很兴奋 它会让你 感到兴奋
happy when you're coming home to your
当你回到家里时很高兴
dog just like okay this is exciting
狗就像没关系这是令人兴奋的
they're always happy when I'm here and
他们总是开心的时候我在这里 ，
if they don't greet you because maybe
如果他们不打招呼， 因为也许
whatever your partner took them on a
无论你的伴侣带他们去做什么
trip or something you might not be
旅行或你 可能 不会的 事情
nearly as happy when you get home right
当你回家的时候几乎一样快乐
and so the kind of it seems like the
所以它看起来像
level of reasoning a dog houses is
狗屋的推理水平
pretty sophisticated but then it's still
相当复杂，但它仍然是
not yet at the level of human reasoning
尚未在 人类推理 的水平
and so it seems like we don't even need
所以我们似乎甚至不需要
to achieve human love reason to get like
实现人类爱情的理由得到喜欢
very strong affection with humans and so
对人类的 非常强烈的感情
my thinking is why not right why
我的想法是为什么不对的原因
couldn't with an AI couldn't we achieve
我们 无法 实现 人工智能
the kind of level of affection that
那种喜爱程度
humans feel among each other or with
人类彼此之间或与之相处
friendly animals and so forth it's a
友好的动物等等
question is it a good thing for us or
问题是一件好事为我们或
not that misses another going right
不是错过了另一个正确的方向
because I mean
因为我的意思
but I don't see why not why not yeah so
但我不明白为什么不为什么不能 这样 呀
he almost says love was the answer maybe
他几乎说爱情可能就是答案
he should say love is the objective
他应该说爱是目标
function and then RL is the answer maybe
功能 然后 RL就是答案
I'll Peter thank you so much I don't
我会 彼得 太感谢你了我不
want to take up more of your time thank
想要占用你更多的时间 谢谢
you so much for talking today well
你今天说得太好了
thanks for coming by great to have you
感谢 伟大的 未来 有你
visit
访问
you
您